

Hassan Aahil Mohamed

FULL STACK ENGINEER

Details

Cyberjaya Malaysia +60 183 757 054 <u>hassan.aahil.m@gmail.com</u>

Links

linkedin.com/in/hassan-aahil-m newhill.github.io

Skills

React
Angular
NodeJS
MongoDB
MySQL
TypeScript
Java
Elastic Search
Ionic
Spring
Liferay DXP
Postman
Puppeteer
Docker
Jenkins
Adobe XD

Full Stack Development

Profile

Hi. I am a seasoned full stack software engineer with over 8 years of experience focused on building robust enterprise solutions and crafting accessible mobile apps and websites.

I love exploring different territories on snorkelling expeditions, as well as on Audible during my runs.

Relevant Experience

Full-stack Developer at Core Systems Integration, Kuala Lumpur

2022 - 2023

- Utilized a diverse tech stack including Spring framework, JSP, HTML, SCSS, jQuery, Liferay DXP and Elastic Search to deliver an <u>Enterprise Platform</u> for Central Bank of Malaysia.
- Led frontend integration with backend, troubleshooting data definitions and quality assurance fixes.
- Experienced in building scalable microservices architecture solution. Created and enhanced utility libraries for code automation.
- Designed report generation and visualization charts via 3rd party integrations, executing custom Boolean queries and index handling using Elasticsearch.
- Handled Application Security Test fixes, including vulnerable library upgrades, code maintenance, and backend deployment.
- Revamped an eKYC onboarding website with a robust camera module, supporting both identification and identity verification using Jumio API.

Software Engineer at DHL IT Services, Cyberjaya

2021 - 2022

- Integral member of the dev team for the <u>DHL Express Mobile App</u>, responsible for continuous fixes, enhancements, and the addition of new features on both frontend and backend.
- Key accomplishments: Managed deployments to Playstore and Appstore, spearheaded Ionic 3 to 5 frontend mobile tech refresh, worked on a new feature release for Shipment module, integrated with 3rd party SDKs for Adobe Analytics and Medallia Customer Experience.
- Worked on Admin Console upgrades built on Angular frontend, NodeJS backend, MongoDB, which included user access management, configuration management, visual dashboards, and integration with Splunk.

Full-stack Web Developer at Supply Network Agency, Cyberjaya

2019 - 2020

- Successfully revamped and redesigned <u>Puffergroup</u>, website, originally built on AppGini.
- Led database redesign (MariaDB), core back-end development and optimization in PHP, Linux back-end server setup, and API function creation using Ajax. Additionally, responsible for UI/UX fixes and creation of Bash scripts for metrics collection.
- Introduced significant features such as web notifications, single sign-on, social interaction between colleagues, automated metric collection and reporting feature, and easy file upload drag-and-drop feature, among others.
- Responsible for the initial research and study of existing solutions, debugging
 of existing problems faced by the client, and complete documentation of new
 solutions.

Data Quality Engineer at DXC Technology, Cyberjaya

2019 - 2021

- Worked in a critical role as a Data Quality Analyst, tackling client issues related to data sourced into and reported from the Enterprise Data Warehouse.
- Regularly engaged with finance, sales, marketing, and supply chain end users to monitor and maintain the quality of data feeds, aggregation logic, and reporting layer.
- Responsible for correcting and fixing duplication, incorrect transformation, and missing information via logic tracing, implementing changes in ETL dependencies, and creating or modifying SQL patch scripts.

Software Developer at DXC Technology, Cyberjaya

2018 - 2019

- Served in the R&D team for SeaQuest an in-house Enterprise Database
 Warehouse solution owned by Hewlett-Packard Enterprise.
- Took on the team lead role for the Malaysia team, focusing on developing new and enhancing existing test suites for HP Database Management System.
- Handled a variety of responsibilities including bug fixing, test case design, client software building and releasing, and L4 support.
- Used key technologies such as Unix/Linux Shell & PERL-scripting for individual test and test-suite creation, Jenkins, Electric Commander, HP UFT & ALM for test-automation, and Ionic framework for a mobile app POC for real-time metrics relevant to DB Admins.

Full Stack Developer at Maslaha Tech, Cyberjaya

2018

- Developed and released a hybrid mobile app called <u>Digital Masjid</u>.
- Built on Ionic, NodeJS, Express and MongoDB.
- Key features include events subscription and management, automated push
 notifications using Firebase, rating system, payment gateway for donations
 using SenangPay, search feature, Google Maps integration, distance calculation
 based on geo-location for event attendance, points collection & redeem system
 and marketplace, account registration and administration.

Database Administrator at Hewlett Packard Enterprise, Cyberjaya

2015 — 2017

- Integral part of a team managing and optimizing queries running on the Enterprise Data Warehouse Database.
- Conducted CRUD operations, database maintenance, identified long running queries, generated explain plans, and executed data extraction and documentation.
- Developed new queries and automations for operational and work efficiency improvement.
- Worked with a diverse technology stack including HP-UX / Linux Scripting, Java, SeaQuest, Oracle, and ASP.NET.

Selected Projects

Enterprise Platform (Central Bank of Malaysia)

2022 - 2023

- A one-stop SaaS enterprise solution streamlining workflows, service desk, publications, submissions, and access management.
- Key experience in deploying scalable microservices solution.
- Public Link: BNM Website

DHL Express Mobile App (Deutsche Post DHL Group)

2021 - 2022

- A customer-centric mobile app for DHL, featuring shipment tracking, delivery management, schedule pickup or drop-off, service point location, shipping rates.
- Links: Playstore: Rating 4.5, Appstore: Rating 4.7

Puffergroup Website (Supply Chain Agency Pvt Ltd)

2019 - 2020

- Provides an infrastructure for virtual deployment of enterprise systematic transformation.
- Link: Puffergroup Website

Digital Masjid Mobile App (Maslaha Tech Pvt Ltd)

2018 - 2019

- An interactive hub for Muslims to engage with various Mosques activities.
- Rating of 3.7 as of Nov 2019 when support and dev was handed over to client.
- Link: Currently unlisted, view on ApkPure.

Education

Master of Business Administration, Anglia Ruskin University, UK

2016 - 2017

Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science, International Islamic University Malaysia, Gombak

2012 - 2015

• Graduated with high honors (GPA 3.88/4)

Certificates

React Native, Deutsche Post DHL Group

2022

Full Stack Web Security, Web Security Academy

2021

Advanced JavaScript HTML5 using AngularJS, TEKsystems

2015